(Leonard:)I don't think it matters
if this is a stalemate
(Leonard:)or an impasse
or a Mexican standoff.
(Leonard:)What are we gonna do here?
(Man:)Oh, whoa, whoa, how can it be
a Mexican standoff?
(Man:)Everybody knows you need
three sides for that.
(Sheldon:)Not necessarily.
(Sheldon:)Uh, many argue the essence
of a Mexican standoff
(Sheldon:)is that no one can walk
away from the conflict
(Sheldon:)without incurring harm.
(Man:)Hmm, I don't follow.
(Sheldon:)Let me give you an example.
(Sheldon:)Earlier today,
(Sheldon:)I decoded the headers
on your e-mail,
(Sheldon:)and I know that your name is
Kenneth Fitzgerald.
(Sheldon:)From that, I figured out where
you live and where you work.
(Sheldon:)Now, to make this
a Mexican standoff,
(Sheldon:)I would say something like, uh,
“You give us the helium or I'll
turn you in to the authorities”"
(Man:)Is that a threat?
(Sheldon:)Yeah, exactly.
See, you're getting it.
(Man:)Yeah, well, I know
where you work, all right?
(Man:)And if you mess with me,
I'll report you,
(Man:)then I'll pound your asses
into the ground.
Perfect! Now we really are
in a Mexican standoff.
(Sheldon:)Is this one of those times
(Sheldon:)where I've won the battle
but lost the war?